Hey.
Hej.
EPISODE 7
ODCINEK 7
Come on.
Przestań.
It's not just my fault.
To nie tylko moja wina.
Right now,
Teraz...
I'm with Miho.
jestem z Miho.
Listen. This isn't just my problem.
Słuchaj. To nie jest tylko mój problem,
This is our problem.
ale nasz wspólny.
Right?
Rozumiesz?
Okay.
Dobrze.
Take care of this, Director.
Zajmij się tym, dyrektorze.
I'm back.
Wróciłem.
So, what do you want to do?
Na co masz ochotę?
You must be hungry.
Musisz być głodna.
What do you want to eat?
Co chcesz zjeść?
Well, okay. Why don't we see a movie?
No dobrze. To może pójdziemy do kina?
Miho.
Miho.
It isn't easy when a friend dies. It would make anyone sad.
Po śmierci przyjaciela nie jest łatwo. Każdemu byłoby smutno.
But you see,
Wiesz...
I like to see you happy, Miho.
chcę, żebyś była szczęśliwa.
So,
Chciałbym...
I want you to be happy when you're with me.
żebyś była szczęśliwa ze mną.
I understand.
Rozumiem.
I need to be optimistic.
Więcej optymizmu.
Right. Okay, let's get something to eat.
Właśnie. Dobrze, zjedzmy coś.
How about that café?
Może w tamtej kawiarni?
That place with the view of the ocean.
Tej z widokiem na ocean.
You remember, right?
Pamiętasz ją?
Let's go there.
Jedźmy tam.
Okay.
Dobrze.
She had a strong sense of justice.
Miała silne poczucie sprawiedliwości.
She should have lived long but she's dead now,
Powinna była żyć długo, ale umarła,
while people who should be dead are still alive.
a osoby, które na to nie zasługują, żyją nadal.
That's wrong.
To nie w porządku.
Anyway, let's go.
Nieważne, jedźmy.
More. This world needs more.
Więcej. Świat potrzebuje więcej.
This world needs more justice.
Więcej sprawiedliwości.
I've had enough.
Mam dość.
I don't care what happens now.
Nie obchodzi mnie, co będzie dalej.
Don't talk like that.
Nie mów tak.
I'm fed up!
Mam dość!
Get rid of someone! I don't care who!
Niech ktoś zniknie! Nieważne kto!
Quit shouting!
Nie krzycz!
If Mr. Hayashi didn't bring us here,
Skoro to nie pan Hayashi nas tu ściągnął,
then who did?
to kto to zrobił?
I thought we would be forgiven if we confessed about Perfect,
Myślałam, że kiedy wyznamy grzechy Idealnej, wybaczy nam.
but it didn't work.
Ale tak się nie stało.
What's under this floor?
Co jest pod podłogą?
Where was Mr. Hayashi taken?
Gdzie zniknął pan Hayashi?
Ayaka.
Ayaka.
What about those weird screams and that earthquake?
A te dziwne krzyki i trzęsienie ziemi?
I don't think that was an earthquake.
To chyba nie było trzęsienie ziemi.
And those screams sounded like something scraping,
A krzyki przypominały raczej drapanie,
-so... -So what?
- więc... - Więc?
Who cares where we are?
Co to za różnica, gdzie jesteśmy?
-Mana! -What?
- Mana! - Co?
Mr. Hayashi tried to destroy that mounted deer head.
Pan Hayashi próbował zniszczyć tamtą głowę jelenia.
Is there someone
Czy ktoś nas...
watching us through it?
przez nią podgląda?
Mr. Hayashi said,
Pan Hayashi powiedział...
"Whatever you look at, it reminds you of something."
że wszystko, co widzimy, z czymś nam się kojarzy.
If we're going to get out of here,
To jedyny sposób...
that's the only way.
żeby się stąd wydostać.
Mana, let's work together.
Mana, współpracujmy.
Okay?
Dobrze?
Let's all get out of here.
Wydostańmy się stąd.
A medical book?
Podręcznik medyczny?
There are many pictures of sisters.
Dużo tu zdjęć sióstr.
Sisters?
Sióstr?
You're right. I hadn't noticed.
Faktycznie. Nie zauważyłam.
They look like they get along,
Wydają się dogadywać,
but they all look kind of sad.
ale wszystkie są jakieś smutne.
Look at that one.
Spójrz na te.
This one?
Te?
I think I've seen it before.
Chyba znam ten obraz.
-Really? -Quit making things up.
- Naprawdę? - Nie kłam.
Hold on. Let me think where I have seen it.
Zaraz. Przypomnę sobie, gdzie go widziałam.
Hurry up and remember.
Pospiesz się.
-Hurry. -Be quiet!
- Pospiesz się. - Cicho!
Hurry up and remember.
No już, przypomnij sobie.
-Wait! -What?
- Czekajcie! - Co?
It's no good. I can't remember.
Nie mogę. Nie pamiętam.
-Seriously? -Are you kidding me?
- Naprawdę? - Żartujesz sobie?
What?
Co?
Look at this!
Patrzcie na to!
I can't see that.
Nie widzę.
What?
Co?
Seriously?
Naprawdę?
Let us see it too.
Nam też pokaż.
That's the picture.
To ten obraz.
Why is that here?
Czemu jest tutaj?
Isn't that...
To chyba
Okazaki's place.
dom Okazakiego.
Right, the villa of Miho's boyfriend.
Tak, willa chłopaka Miho.
When was that?
Kiedy to było?
Wasn't it the Golden Week?
Podczas Złotego Tygodnia?
But why is that painting here?
Ale czemu ten obraz jest tutaj?
Mirei.
Mirei.
Forget it. She's in the zone again.
Zostaw ją, znowu odpłynęła.
It was the same seven people as now.
To była ta sama siódemka.
What?
Co?
Remember?
Pamiętacie?
We're the ones who were with Miho at the villa.
Nasza siódemka była z Miho w tej willi.
The seven of us.
Właśnie my.
Seriously?
Naprawdę?
It's just a coincidence.
To musi być przypadek.
Ayaka.
Ayaka.
Kyoko.
Kyoko.
Kumi.
Kumi.
Memi.
Memi.
Mana.
Mana.
Shiho.
Shiho.
Me.
Ja.
That means,
To znaczy...
it was planned that we would be the only ones left.
że miałyśmy zostać tylko my.
That's...
Czyli...
-Are you saying it's Okazaki? -Impossible.
- Uważasz, że to Okazaki? - To niemożliwe.
Then why is that same painting here?
To skąd ten obraz?
Why would Okazaki do this?
Po co Okazaki miałby to zrobić?
For revenge.
Z zemsty.
We're the ones
To my...
who bullied his girlfriend, Miho, and forced her to disappear.
dręczyłyśmy jego dziewczynę, Miho, i zmusiłyśmy ją do zniknięcia.
I don't think Okazaki has anything to do with this.
Wątpię, że to Okazaki.
What? Did you say something?
Co? Mówiłaś coś?
I found it!
Znalazłam!
This is a video from back then.
Filmik z tej imprezy.
Thank you.
Dzięki.
Yes!
Tak!
There you go. Do you like it?
Proszę. Smakuje ci?
Yes! It's great!
Tak, jest pyszne!
You really like meat, Shiho.
Naprawdę lubisz mięso, Shiho.
Hey! What's that supposed to mean?
Hej! Co to ma znaczyć?
-Do you want some? -Can I have it?
- Chcesz trochę? - Mogę?
Sure. Thanks.
Jasne. Dzięki.
Thank you.
Dziękuję.
This is really good!
To naprawdę pyszne!
That's it?
To wszystko?
Well,
Cóż...
yes.
tak.
That's the first time I have heard Shiho's voice in a while.
Pierwszy raz od dawna słyszałam głos Shiho.
Hey, when did you stop talking?
Kiedy przestałaś mówić?
Kyoko, give me the phone.
Kyoko, daj mi telefon.
-I want to search too. -Okay.
- Też chcę poszukać. - Jasne.
I have one too.
Też coś mam.
Shiho, today...
Shiho, dzisiaj...
Hey, everyone. Listen up.
Hej, posłuchajcie.
What is this about?
O co chodzi?
Stop eating.
Przestańcie jeść.
Miho, come here.
Chodź, Miho.
Actually,
Dokładnie...
one year ago on the same day,
rok temu, tego samego dnia,
On May 3rd, Miho and I started dating.
trzeciego maja, Miho i ja zaczęliśmy się spotykać.
Seriously?
Naprawdę?
Miho, I hope to continue dating you.
Miho, mam nadzieję, że dalej będziemy razem.
Congratulations.
Gratulacje.
-Congratulations.
- Gratulacje.
Thanks.
Dziękuję.
Miho, smile for everyone.
Uśmiechnij się, Miho.
What is wrong, Miho? You seem a little depressed.
Co się stało? Wydajesz się smutna.
Here's your favorite, Miho, hamburger. Have some.
Proszę, to twój ulubiony hamburger.
Oh, right.
O właśnie.
He's so conceited.
Jest taki zarozumiały.
That reminds me.
Pamiętam, jak kiedyś
He told me his parents have a yacht even though I never asked.
powiedział mi, że jego rodzice mają jacht. Wcale nie pytałam!
Seriously?
Naprawdę?
I hate guys like that.
Nie znoszę takich facetów.
I hate them too.
Ja też.
Come to think of it,
Tak właściwie,
why did we go to his villa anyway?
to czemu poszłyśmy do tej willi?
Wasn't it Kumi who invited us?
Chyba Kumi nas zaprosiła.
I organized it because Miho was really depressed then.
Zorganizowałam imprezę, bo Miho była bardzo smutna.
She was?
Tak?
A friend of ours died. She had been our friend since we were little.
Umarła nasza przyjaciółka z dzieciństwa.
A friend since you were little?
Przyjaciółka z dzieciństwa?
Is that the same person
Ta sama osoba,
-who... -Who started Perfect?
- która... - Założyła Idealną?
Of course, I was shocked too when I heard about it.
Oczywiście też byłam w szoku.
But Miho became really depressed.
Ale Miho popadła w depresję.
So Okazaki and I decided to try cheering up Miho.
Okazaki i ja chcieliśmy ją pocieszyć.
Seriously?
Naprawdę?
Miho.
Miho.
I swear
Przyrzekam
that I will love you for the rest of my life.
kochać cię do końca życia.
-Congratulations! -Thank you!
- Gratulacje! - Dzięki!
It's time to make a toast.
Czas na toast!
Here's to the future director.
Za przyszłego dyrektora!
Cheers!
Zdrowie!
-Cheers! -Congratulations!
- Zdrowie! - Gratulacje!
Thank you!
Dziękuję!
Aren't you jealous?
Zazdrosna?
Let me see it, Miho.
Pokaż, Miho.
That's really pretty.
Naprawdę piękny.
-It's beautiful. -That's totally awesome!
- Piękny. - Cudowny.
-Looks good! -That's so nice!
- Dobrze wygląda. - Jaki ładny!
-I want to get married too. -That must have cost a lot.
- Marzę o ślubie. - Pewnie był drogi.
It's a diamond.
To brylant.
However,
Ale...
after that day, Miho became even more depressed.
tamtego dnia Miho posmutniała jeszcze bardziej.
Why?
Dlaczego?
She started accusing Okazaki of having another girlfriend.
Zaczęła oskarżać Okazakiego o umawianie się z inną dziewczyną.
What a scumbag.
Co za dupek.
Can I say something?
Mogę coś powiedzieć?
Mana, why have you been silent?
Czemu milczysz, Mana?
What?
Co?
What are you hiding?
Co ukrywasz?
-I'm not hiding anything. -Then show me that.
- Nic! - To pokaż mi to.
Quit accusing me!
Przestań mnie oskarżać!
We aren't accusing you.
Nikt cię nie oskarża.
What's wrong?
Co się stało?
I'm not hiding anything.
Niczego nie ukrywam.
It might help us get out of here.
To może nam pomóc w ucieczce.
Okay, Mana?
Dobrze, Mana?
There's nothing on my phone.
Nie mam nic na telefonie.
Hold on.
Czekaj.
I have a photo here.
Mam zdjęcie.
This is totally true.
To prawda.
See?
Widzisz?
What's that about?
O co tu chodzi?
Mirei wore contacts on that day, instead of eyeglasses.
Mirei założyła wtedy soczewki zamiast okularów.
So?
No i?
What about it?
Co w związku z tym?
Look at her face.
Patrzcie na jej twarz.
She's acting all cutesy.
Jest taka słodziutka.
I wasn't! My glasses were broken that day.
Nieprawda! Okulary mi się połamały.
-You look smart, but you're actually sly. -What does that have to do with anything?
- Wyglądasz na mądrą, ale jesteś cwana. - Co w związku z tym?
You started this, Mirei!
Ty zaczęłaś, Mirei!
What is with you two?
O co wam chodzi?
-What about you? -What?
- Co z tobą? - Co?
You were acting strange then, Mana.
Dziwnie się wtedy zachowywałaś.
What? I was?
Co? Ja?
What do you mean?
O co ci chodzi?
It's hard to explain.
Ciężko to wyjaśnić.
Hey, Mirei! Cut it out! Quit making things up!
Przestań, Mirei! Nie zmyślaj!
-Let me see your phone. -Give it back, Memi!
- Pokaż mi telefon. - Oddaj, Memi.
-What? -Don't!
- Co? - Przestań!
Give it back!
Oddaj!
Hey! That hurts!
Hej, to boli!
I said, that hurts!
Mówię ci, że to boli!
-Sorry. -That hurt.
- Przepraszam. - Bolało.
What's wrong with you, Mana?
O co ci chodzi, Mana?
Why are you so flustered?
Czemu tak zareagowałaś?
Was Okazaki cheating with you?
Okazaki zdradzał Miho z tobą?
No! I wasn't!
Nie!
Hold on.
Czekajcie.
I've remembered some things.
Coś sobie przypominam.
-On our way home that day... -Oh, yes!
- Kiedy wracałyśmy... - Faktycznie!
The bus was about to come,
Czekałyśmy na autobus,
but Mana and Okazaki weren't there.
ale Many i Okazakiego nie było.
Shut up!
Zamknij się!
I remember too.
Też to pamiętam.
Mana and Okazaki were late.
Spóźnili się.
No, we weren't!
To nieprawda!
It was you, right?
To byłaś ty, prawda?
Are you serious?
Poważnie?
I didn't do anything!
Nic nie zrobiłam!
Memi! We're best friends!
Memi! Przyjaźnimy się!
Please! Help me!
Proszę, pomóż mi.
Come to think of it,
Faktycznie...
I remember your cheeks were flushed then.
miałaś wtedy rumieńce.
Why would you say that?
Czemu tak mówisz?
Wait. Hold on, you guys.
Zaraz. Poczekajcie.
I swear! We didn't do anything!
Przysięgam! Nic między nami nie było!
Didn't Mana start bullying Miho
Czy Mana nie zaczęła nękać Miho
right after this barbecue?
zaraz po tym grillu?
Maybe Miho figured out her boyfriend was cheating on her with Mana.
Może Miho zorientowała się, że Okazaki zdradzał ją z Maną.
You made me bully Miho because of that?
Kazałaś mi dręczyć Miho przez takie coś?
You dragged me into this
Wciągnęłaś mnie w to,
because you were fooling around with her boyfriend?
żeby zabawiać się z jej chłopakiem?
No, I wasn't, Memi! I mean...
Nie, Memi! Ja...
You fucking bitch!
Jebana dziwko!
-Stop it, Memi! -God damn you! You bitch!
- Przestań, Memi! - Niech cię szlag, suko!
-Stop! I didn't do it! -You're not my friend!
- Nic nie zrobiłam! - To koniec przyjaźni!
-I didn't do it! -You bitch!
- Suka!
-Fuck you!
- To nie ja! - Pierdol się!
-Memi! -God damn you!
- Memi! - Niech cię szlag!
What are these?
Co to?
What?
Co?
Give it back! Please!
Oddaj, proszę!
-These are all photos of Okazaki. -Give it back!
- Same zdjęcia Okazakiego. - Oddaj!
-Let me see. -Look.
- Pokaż. - Patrzcie.
Give it back!
Oddajcie to!
Please! Give it back!
Proszę, oddajcie!
There are photos that aren't from the barbecue.
To nie są zdjęcia z grilla.
-Look at this. -Stop!
- Patrz na to. - Przestańcie!
I'll talk.
Dobrze, powiem.
I'll tell you about it.
Powiem wam wszystko.
Please. Give it back.
Ale proszę, oddajcie mi telefon.
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
I...
Ja...
was in love with Okazaki.
zakochałam się w Okazakim.
Really?
Naprawdę?
I fell in love with him.
Zakochałam się w nim.
I thought so.
Tak myślałam.
Kyoko.
Kyoko.
When he and Miho started dating,
Kiedy on i Miho zaczęli się spotykać,
I ran into them one day.
raz na nich wpadłam.
The three of us went to a café.
Poszliśmy razem do kawiarni.
That was the time
Wtedy Okazaki
Okazaki started calling me by my first name.
zaczął mi mówić po imieniu.
That made me fall for him.
Zakochałam się w nim.
It was love at first sight.
Od pierwszego wejrzenia.
There's nothing special about that.
Potraktował cię zwyczajnie.
You fell in love with another girl's boyfriend because of that?
Tak po prostu zakochałaś się w chłopaku koleżanki?
Then,
Potem...
I read through Okazaki's Twitter feed.
czytałam Twittera Okazakiego.
I went alone to the places where they went on dates.
Chodziłam sama do miejsc, w których się spotykali.
Really?
Naprawdę?
I went to the hospital to watch him work.
Poszłam do szpitala, żeby zobaczyć go przy pracy.
What? That's weird.
Co? To dziwne.
Do you know the password to Miho's phone?
Znasz hasło do telefonu Miho?
No.
Nie.
Miho
Hasło Miho to...
made her password the date she and Okazaki started dating, May 3.
trzeci maja, data rozpoczęcia ich związku.
I accessed Miho's phone and got Okazaki's number.
Dostałam się do telefonu Miho i zdobyłam numer Okazakiego.
I made prank calls and hung up several times.
Dzwoniłam do niego i się rozłączałam.
What a total stalker.
Prześladowałaś go?
That's all I did! I swear!
Nie zrobiłam nic więcej! Przysięgam!
"That's all"?
„Nic więcej”?
What a bitch.
Suka z ciebie.
It was the first time I had fallen in love.
Pierwszy raz w życiu się zakochałam.
I didn't know what to do.
Nie wiedziałam, co robić.
During the barbecue, Okazaki served me meat and stuff.
Podczas grilla Okazaki podawał mi mięso.
Our eyes kept meeting.
Ciągle na siebie spoglądaliśmy.
I couldn't hold back my feelings for him any longer.
Nie mogłam już ukrywać swoich uczuć...
So, when we were leaving, I pulled him aside
więc kiedy wychodziliśmy, wzięłam go na stronę...
and told him my feelings.
i powiedziałam, co czuję.
I said, "I love you."
Powiedziałam, że go kocham...
He turned me down.
a on mnie odrzucił.
But,
Ale...
he said, "I don't hate you though."
powiedział, że mnie nie nienawidzi.
He only said that because...
Powiedział to tylko po to...
Hearing those words made me so happy.
Te słowa mnie ucieszyły.
Look, Mana. What he meant was...
Mana, jemu chodziło o to, że...
"I don't hate you" means "I might like you," right?
„Nie nienawidzę cię” może zamienić się w „lubię cię”, prawda?
How can you be so naive? What an idiot.
Jak możesz być tak naiwna? Kretynka.
Don't tell me you're still stalking him.
Nie mów, że dalej go prześladujesz.
I'm not a stalker!
Nie prześladowałam go!
Yes, you definitely are.
Robiłaś to.
Miho doesn't know about that, right?
Miho o tym nie wie, prawda?
No.
Nie.
But, after the barbecue,
Ale po grillu...
I told Miho about it.
coś jej powiedziałam.
I said
Powiedziałam jej...
Okazaki is
że Okazaki...
a scumbag boyfriend, and she should break up with him.
to dupek i powinna z nim zerwać.
You lied to her?
Okłamałaś ją?
It wasn't a lie.
Nie kłamałam.
I wanted him for myself.
Chciałam go dla siebie.
But after that, Miho started bullying me.
Ale potem Miho zaczęła mnie dręczyć.
Before I knew it, I got Memi involved.
Nim się obejrzałam, wciągnęłam w to Memi.
That's why we bullied her.
Dlatego nękałyśmy Miho.
Memi shouldn't be blamed. It's all my fault.
Memi nie jest winna, tylko ja.
I'm sorry, Memi.
Przepraszam, Memi.
Memi.
Memi.
-What?
- Co?
-Help me! -What's wrong?
- Pomocy! - Co się stało?
-Water?
- Woda?
-Mana! -Oh, God!
- Mana! - Boże!
Oh, God! Help me, Memi!
Boże! Memi, pomocy!
Okazaki! Forgive her!
Okazaki! Wybacz jej!
Please!
Błagam!
No! Okazaki isn't doing this!
Nie! To nie Okazaki!
How would you know?
Skąd wiesz?
Okazaki broke up with Miho. He has a new girlfriend!
Okazaki zerwał z Miho i znalazł sobie nową dziewczynę!
What? They broke up?
Co? Rozstali się?
He would never do this to Miho!
Nie zrobiłby tego dla Miho!
Where did you learn that?
Skąd to wiesz?
I know everything about Okazaki!
Wiem wszystko o Okazakim!
You bitch!
Suko!
You're hiding something, but you are just staying silent.
Ukrywasz coś, ale milczysz!
What are you talking about?
O czym ty mówisz?
I know all about it!
Wiem wszystko!
Are you hiding something, Shiho?
Ukrywasz coś, Shiho?
Come on! Tell us!
Hej! Powiedz nam!
You and Okazaki...
Ty i Okazaki...
Memi!
Memi!
Mana!
Mana!
I'm so sorry! It's all my fault!
Przepraszam! To moja wina!
I can't take this!
Nie wytrzymam!
Shiho.
Shiho.
What do you know about Okazaki?
Co wiesz o Okazakim?
Come on, Shiho!
Shiho, powiedz nam!
What are you hiding?
Co ukrywasz?
That hurt.
To bolało.
What?
Co?
Damn you!
Niech cię szlag!
THIS DRAMA IS A WORK OF FICTION.
PRZEDSTAWIONY SERIAL JEST FIKCJĄ.
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey
Napisy: Arianna Sugier